# FENIL DOSHI

fenil\_doshi@fas.harvard.edu \( \phi \) www.fenildoshi.com

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am broadly interested in how the human mind encodes and organizes visual sensory information into mid- and high-level representations. In my research, I combine computational models of vision and behavioral psychophysics, to probe how emergent properties of a hierarchical visual processor both support and limit complex cognition.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Harvard University, Cambridge, MA

2021 - Present

Ph.D. in Psychology (Cognition, Brain, and Behavior) Advisor: Dr. George Alvarez and Dr. Talia Konkle

# SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, India

2014 - 2018

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (GPA: 8.65/10.0)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Harvard University, Dept. of Psychology

Nov 2018 - Present

Research Assistant (Fellow), Vision Sciences Lab

Faculty Advisor: Dr. George A. Alvarez & Dr. Talia Konkle

Focus: Information processing in human vision and bottlenecks underlying complex cognition:

- 1. Explored the underlying principles governing the large-scale organization of object information in occipito-temporal cortex.
- 2. Trained generative models (variational autoencoders) and conducted behavioral psychophysics to discover representations that can explain high-level human judgements in intuitive physics tasks.
- 3. Used gradient-based methods to synthesize stimuli that maximally drive neural activity in primate V4 layer of the visual cortex and build models of capacity-limits in human visual working memory.

#### Harvard Medical School (BWH)

Jan 2018 - July 2018

Research Intern, Shafiee Lab

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Hadi Shafiee

Focus:

Trained convolutional neural networks to identify and qualitatively analyze the structural morphology of cells. Optimized the models to deal with class imbalance using class-sensitive training and sampling.

## IIIT-Delhi, Dept. of Computer Science

June 2017 - Aug 2017

Summer Research Intern

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Saket Anand

Focus:

Lane detection on urban roads using semantic segmentation in autonomous vehicles.

UW-Madison Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

Visiting student

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Dane Morgan

Focus

Used bayesian models and neural networks to predict changes in the mechanical properties of steel components due to alloy configurations.

#### Conference Proceedings

- 1. **Doshi, F.**, Konkle, T.(2021). Organizational motifs of cortical responses to objects emerge in topographic projections of deep neural networks. Talk presented at *Vision Sciences Society*, 2021.
- 2. **Doshi, F.**, Pailian, H., Alvarez, G.A.(2020). Using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks to Examine the Role of Representational Similarity in Visual Working Memory. In *Vision Science Society*, 2020.
- 3. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.(2019). Shared Representations of Stability in Humans, Supervised, & Unsupervised Neural Networks. In *Shared Visual Representations in Human and Machine Intelligence (SVRHM) workshop at NeurIPS 2019*.
- 4. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.(2019). Human-Like Judgments of Stability Emerge from Purely Perceptual Features: Evidence from Supervised and Unsupervised Deep Neural Networks. In *Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience (CCN)*, 2019.
- 5. Thirumalaraju, P., Bormann, CL., Kanakasabapathy, M., **Doshi, F.**, Souter, I., Dimitriadis, I., Shafiee, H.(2018). Automated sperm morpshology testing using artificial intelligence. In *Fertility and sterility.* 2018 Sep 1;110(4):e432.
- 6. Chatterjee, S., Archana, V., Suresh, K., Saha, R., Gupta, R., **Doshi, F.(2017)**.Detection of non-technical losses using advanced metering infrastructure and deep recurrent neural networks. In *IEEE International Conference on Environment and Electrical Engineering*.

# Manuscripts

- 1. **Doshi, F.**, Konkle, T. Organizational motifs of cortical responses to objects emerge in topographic projections of deep neural networks. (Paper in Prep)
- 2. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.. Human-Like Judgments of Stability Emerge from Purely Perceptual Features in Unsupervised and Supervised Models. (Paper in Prep)
- 3. Kanakasabapathy, M., Thirumalaraju, P., Kandula, H., **Doshi, F.**, Sivakumar, A., Kartik, D., Gupta, R., Pooniwala, R., Branda, J., Tsibris, A., Kuritzkes, D., Petrozza, J., Bormann, C., Shafiee H. (2021). Adaptive adversarial neural networks for the analysis of lossy and domain-shifted datasets of medical images. In *Nature Biomedical Engineering*, 2021.

## HONORS AND AWARDS

• Reimagine Education Award (Silver), Student-led Innovation for Next Tech Lab Quacquarelli Symonds (QS), Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania

2018

- Best Outgoing Student, Class of 2018
   Department of Computer Science, SRM Institute of Science and Technology
- National Champion
  Smart India Hackathon (India's biggest Hackathon)

  2017

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

**Programming**: Python (Pytorch, Tensorflow, Theano, Keras), Javascript, Matlab, C, C++, C#, Java **Experimental Techniques**: Computational Modelling, Behavioral Psychophysics **Statistics/Analysis**: Non-parametric statistics, power analyses, simulation, resampling (bootstrapping), model comparison; factor analysis/principal component analysis, singular value decomposition

#### LEADERSHIP & ADVISING EXPERIENCE

## Next Tech Lab, Founding Member and Advisor

Co-founded a student-run research lab at SRM Institute of Science and Technology. Co-led over 160 students concentrating on Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computational Biology, and Mixed Reality(AR/VR).

## SELECT PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Feature-based categorical attention: Taking inspiration from work by Lindsay & Miller (2018), I isolated category-specific neurons in a pre-trained (on ImageNet) deep net (VGG-19). Category-wise normalized activation profiles were computed at the resolution of individual neurons and compared with the corresponding normalized gradient-based profiles/curves. Those neurons whose tuning and gradient profiles correlated significantly (hence had behavioral outcomes) were selected. Further analysis (t-tests) provided a stronger selection criterion. During the forward pass, these neurons are then modulated to improve categorization. An open question is to disentangle the attentional signals carried in feedforward, lateral, and top-down connections.
- Exploring the latent feature space of face representations in a reconstruction-based network using Deep Feature Consistency: Trained an adversarial variational autoencoder on the CelebA dataset. The KL divergence loss was replaced with an adversarial loss (Makhzani et al., 2016) and the pixel-wise loss was replaced with a deep feature consistent loss (Hou et al., 2016). Smooth interpolations in this latent space showed that the model was able to capture certain semantic aspects of different facial attributes.
- Neural Artistic Style Transfer for Videos: Produced results on a frame-by-frame basis and later improved it by initializing every new frame using optical flow from the previous frames.
- Retrieving the latent space of a Generative Adversarial Network (input noise): Designed an auxiliary GAN model with a cyclic network to map the generated image space back to its latent space. The discriminator was designed with an additional patch-based loss function and optimized with label smoothing.
- **Deep Sense:** A Restricted Boltzmann Machine (RBM) trained on a bunch of different songs by Hans Zimmer to produce novel monophonic music in his style.